Then this machine was-
では　この機体は…
Yeah. The demon we
saw 15 years ago.
ああ　15年前の悪夢さ
I always figured it had been annihilated
in the damage of Heaven's Fall.
ヘブンズ・フォールの被害で消滅したとばかり思ってたぜ
Capt. Magbaredge!
マグバレッジ艦長
What in the world... is that?
何ですか　これは
Confirm that the ship
is fitted out.
艤装を確認　燃料　武器　弾薬を調べてください
Check its fuel, weapons,
and munitions.
Yes, ma'am!
了解
Deucalion. That's this ship's name?
デューカリオン　この船の名
Why do you suppose such a
fine ship was abandoned
こんな立派な船が　何故出撃もせず　放置されているのでしょう
without ever sending it
into battle?
Reserves are still working! If we can
feed it power, it'll be good to go.
予備電源　生きてます
パワーが来ればいけます
Fuel level is...
I'm not sure!
燃料は　分かりません
What kind of report is that?
何だ　その報告は
There's no fuel gauge!
だって　無いんです燃料計が
Oh, so that's it.
そういう事ですか
That's why this ship
was abandoned.
この船が放棄された理由です
Surely you don't mean...
まさか…
An Aldnoah drive.
アルドノアドライブ
Hey, civilians aren't
allowed in here!
駄目ですよ　ここは民間人は　早く外に
Please leave imme-
My apologies.
失礼
Who are you?!
何者
There is no cause for alarm.
I am your friend.
心配は要りません　私は　皆さんの友達です
You're...
あなたは…
I command you in the name
of Asseylum Vers Allusia!
アセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシアの名において
Aldnoah, awaken!
目覚めよ　アルドノア
君が見る夢は　古いインクで紙に書いた祈りのよう
小さなその手が　縋るものも　今はまだ何処にも無い
それでも君の行く道を
奇麗なものは奇麗なままで　守り続けたいと思うよ
空と水が星を染めて
淡く虹を描いて散って
眩しい夜　君が歌う
声は何処まで届くのだろう
憧れの住まう蒼い星のひかり
ただ僕らは恋をして
たったひとつの未来の為に
今の全て奏でてみる
飛び立つよ　まだ暗い空へ
Well? Are we in a more
talkative mood now?
どうだ　少しは話す気になったか
What is your objective?
貴様の目的は何だ
To what end did you
go to that island?
何をしにあの島へ行った
Perhaps he has had enough,
Count Cruhteo.
そのくらいにしては如何か　クルーテオ卿
We needn't show pity to a member
of a lower race, Count Saazbaum.
劣等民族に情けは必要無かろう　ザーツバルム卿
If he dies, we learn nothing.
死んでしまっては元も子もない
He sought an audience with the emperor,
heedless of the risk to himself.
身の危険を顧みず　皇帝に謁見など余程の事
That is remarkable.
I would know his intent.
その真意を知りたい
Intent?
真意　こんな子供に考えなどあろうものか
As if this child
is capable of thought.
Milord Cruhteo. We have
located the wreckage
クルーテオ伯爵
島で　軌道騎士のカタフラクトの残骸を発見しました
of an Orbital Knight Kataphrakt
on the island.
What?
何
We believe it to be that of
Countess Femieanne's Hellas.
フェミーアン伯爵のヘラスと思われます
何と…
How can that be?
What was Countess Femieanne slain by?
フェミーアン伯爵は何にうたれた
時間の無駄か
A waste of time, eh?
Abide, Count Cruhteo.
待たれよ　クルーテオ卿
Tell me now! If you do,
I will put you out of your misery.
早く吐け　そうすれば楽にしてやろう
Continue to suffer, then.
ならばもっと苦しめ
So this is the bridge...
これがブリッジ…
Deucalion... A flying battleship.
デューカリオン　空飛ぶ戦艦
Nina, what makes it fly?
ニーナ　これどうやって飛んでるの
火星の　例の
That Martian thing, uh...
Aldnoah?
アルドノア
ああ　それ
Yeah, that.
操船は普通の船と同じなのか　お前でも大丈夫なの
Are the helm controls like a normal ship's?
Can you handle this thing?
The FCS has been adjusted so it
feels the same when I steer.
同じ感覚で操舵出来るようにFCSが調整されているの
持ち場を離れてもいいの　カーム
Should you be away from
your post, Calm?
What's the big deal if I want
to look around a bit?
いいだろ　少しくらい見学したって　偉い人居ないんだし
Besides, there's no
bigwigs around.
Hm? Where's Inaho?
あれ　ってか　伊奈帆は
その偉い人ん所　火星人と一緒に
In the bigwig's office.
With the Martians.
Martians...
火星人
うん　おかげでこの船のアルドノアドライブが起動したのよ
Yeah. Thanks to her, this ship's
Aldnoah drive is working.
What?!
何
The Mars Knights plotted your assassination?
I find that hard to believe.
火星騎士が殿下の暗殺を　にわかに信じ難いお話です
マグバレッジ艦長　この事を明らかにすれば
Capt. Magbaredge, if we disclosed this information,
perhaps the Mars Knights would stop attacking.
火星騎士は攻撃を止めるのでは
Our communications satellites and
telecom bases have been wiped out,
通信衛星及び通信基地は全滅
and long-range transmissions are impossible
thanks to their jamming signal.
妨害電波によって　長距離無線も不可能
If we're going to try to get the word
out that the princess is safe,
殿下の無事を伝えようにも　然るべき機関に正確に伝わるとは限りません
there's no guarantee that the proper
agencies would get the message.
You believe it would make us the target of
the Mars Knights who plotted her death?
むしろ　暗殺を企てた火星騎士の攻撃の的になると
Our plan all along was to go to United
Earth HQ in Russia to regroup, anyway.
元々我々は　ロシアの地球連合本部に合流する予定でした
Very well. Until we arrive, we will
see to your safety, Highness.
いいでしょう　到着まで殿下を保護致します
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Now, Kaizuka Junior.
それで　界塚弟
Inaho Kaizuka, ma'am.
界塚伊奈帆です
それと…
And you...
Rayet Areash.
ライエ・アリアーシュ
二人共　この事実を知りながら　報告を怠っていたわけですね
You two were aware of this,
yet neglected to inform me.
私は軍人じゃない　報告義務も無い
I'm not a soldier. I'm not
obligated to report to you.
And you, Junior?
弟君は
I didn't neglect to inform you.
I deliberately didn't.
怠ったのではありません　故意に報告しませんでした
Watch what you say! You're putting
yourself on very thin ice.
発言に注意しなさい　立場が不利になりますよ
I asked him not to.
私がそうお願いしたのです
この船に　暗殺者の仲間が居ないとも限りませんし
Someone working with the
assassins might be aboard.
Eddelrittuo!
エデルリッゾ
信用出来ないのは火星人も同じ
We can't trust you Martians, either.
A nation that latched onto
an archaic feudal system
アルドノアという古代文明の超科学を頼りに
古臭い封建制度にしがみついた民族
that relies on the superscience of an
ancient civilization called Aldnoah.
Commoners who are obsessed with proving
themselves in battle to win social standing.
位を得たいばかりに　武勲を上げる事に躍起になる平民
And nobility who casually betray them
and grind them into the dirt...
それを平気で裏切り　踏みにじる貴族
How can you possibly
trust people like that?!
そんな奴らを　どうやって信じるの
I don't trust them.
私は信じない　火星人は　皆敵
All Martians are the enemy!
No matter how far science advances, these
procedures always remain primitive.
如何に科学が進歩しようとも　この手の処置は常に原始的
And at times... are all the
more effective for it.
そして時には　その方が効果が高い
Do it.
やれ
Does it hurt?
痛いか
Now, then...
さあ　どうした
What is the matter?
Oh, has that loosened
your tongue?
何か言いたくなったか
Have you... sworn loyalty...
あなたは　アセイラム姫に忠誠を　誓っていますか
...to Princess Asseylum?
続けろ
Continue.
Yes, Milord!
生意気な小僧が
Impudent boy...
And how are we feeling?
気分はどうですか
最低だ
Lousy...
Glad to hear it. The medicine
seems to be working.
良かった　薬が効いたみたいですね
I can't believe that coming here
triggered a relapse...
まさかここに来て再発とは
I'd feel a lot better if
you'd give me some booze.
酒をくれれば　もっと良くなるんだがな
That's not the sort of medicine
you pester your doctor for.
医者にねだる薬じゃありませんね
I hate this...
最低だ
"Birds"?
鳥
Yes, Milady.
はい
Animals that fly
through the air...
空を飛ぶ生き物　地球に行けば　見る事が出来るのですね
When we reach Earth, I will be
able to see them, won't I?
Yes. Progress is slow, but the scars
of Heaven's Fall are fading.
はい　少しずつですが
ヘブンズ・フォールの傷跡も回復しています
Nature is powerful, and when
an area is depopulated,
自然の力は強くて　人間が居なくなると急速に回復を始めるんです
it immediately begins
to reclaim it.
Depopulated?
人間が居なくなると
Yes. As opposed
to urban areas,
はい　都市部とは逆に　壊滅した地域は　緑が多く繁殖して
plant life reproduces abundantly
in devastated regions, and...
It is sad, isn't it? That we are
unable to thrive together.
悲しいですね　一緒に繁栄する事が出来ないなんて
Not at all! With forethought
and hard work, it is possible!
そんな事はありません　ちゃんと考えて努力すれば　可能です
Do you really think so?
そうなのですか
Yes! It is possible for us
to thrive together!
はい　共に繁栄する事は出来るんです
Well, Terran? Do you feel
like talking now?
どうだ地球人　何か話す気になったか
Count... Do you care for
the princess?
伯爵は　姫をお慕いしてますか
What?
何
Are you... her ally?
伯爵は　味方ですか
Yes. Of course I am.
ああ　味方だとも
Now, speak.
さあ　吐け
As punishment for your crime,
貴様の罪の裁きとして　地球の仲間に更なる恐怖を味わわせてやろう
I shall give your compatriots on Earth
a taste of even greater horrors.
I knew it, you were lying...
やっぱり嘘だ　あなたは　地球と戦う理由が欲しいんだ
You want an excuse to go
to war with Earth...
Her Highness wished for
peace with Earth, but you...
姫は　地球との平和を望んでおられたのに
あなたは　姫の死を利用して　姫の夢を　壊している
You are exploiting her death...
...to crush her dream...
Do not invoke her memory
so lightly, you filthy Terran!
地球人風情が　姫の名を軽々しく使うな
Sey-
セラムさん
No, Princess Asseylum.
あ　いえ　アセイラム姫
I do not mind you
calling me Seylum, Inaho.
セラムで構いません　伊奈帆さん
いいえ　構います
But I mind!
From now on, add
"Your Highness" to that.
今度は殿下も付けてください
Eddeltittuo.
エデルリッゾ
しかし
But, Milady!
申し訳ありません　これも私の事を気遣っての事
I do apologize. This is her way
of looking out for me.
So, what is it?
それで何でしょう
Well, I ran into someone
on Tanegashima who-
実は　種子島で遭遇した…
おーい　伊奈帆
Hey, Inaho!
You knew that there were
Martians hiding among us?
お前　火星人が紛れ込んでるの　知ってたのか
Yeah.
Where are they?!
I'm gonna avenge Okojo!
何処だよそいつ　俺がオコジョの仇を討ってやる
I am the Princess
of Mars you seek.
私がその　火星の皇女です
Come again?
はい？
I deeply regret that so many of your fellow
Terrans have been injured or killed.
多くのお仲間が傷付き　亡くなった事を　心から悼みます
I assure you, this war
is not what Vers wants.
この戦争は決してヴァースの本意ではありません
I am doing all I can to bring this meaningless
conflict to an end as soon as possible.
無意味な争いを　一刻も早く終わらせるよう　努力致します
Uh... Sure.
Do your best, okay?
え　あ　はい
頑張って
What are you blushing for?
何赤くなってるの
You're as red as a lobster.
タコみたい
何だよいきなり…
Where did you guys
come from?!
仇討つんじゃなかったの
Didn't you say you were
going to get revenge?
Didn't you say something about
all Martians being the enemy?
火星人は全員敵だって言ってなかった
I never said any such thing!
そんな事言ってねえよ
火星人だからって　良い奴と　悪い奴が居んだろ
There are good Martians and bad
Martians, same as everywhere else!
Right, Inaho?
なあ　伊奈帆
Back my play, man!
フォローしろよ
As I said, there's no
trusting Terrans...
やはり地球人は信用出来ません
You have saved me countless times
since we arrived on Earth, Inaho.
地球に来て以来　伊奈帆さんには何度も助けられました
Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます
I wasn't fighting for you
in particular, Seylum.
別に　セラムさんの為に戦ったわけじゃない
It's because I was drafted. If I don't
fight, it puts me in danger, too.
召集されたから　戦わなければ　僕自身も危ないし
でも　助けられた事に変わりはありません　ありがとうございます
Nevertheless, that does not change
the fact that I owe you my life.
Thank you.
That Martian that I met on
Tanegashima was looking for you.
種子島で遭遇した火星人　あなたの事を探していました
And he was scared that you
were being exploited.
そして　あなたが利用される事を恐れていた
Could it be...?
それって…
There are some among the enemy
who think that you are still alive.
敵の中には　あなたがまだ生きていると思っている者が居ます
I suggest staying
on your guard.
警戒するに越した事は無い
What's that?
それは…
地球に来る時　親しい地球人に貰ったお守りです
A good luck charm given to me by a dear
Terran friend when we arrived at Earth.
By a Terran?
地球人に
The son of a scientist who
visited Mars to study Aldnoah.
アルドノアの研究で　ヴァースに訪れた科学者の息子さんです
I heard all manner of stories
regarding Earth from him.
その方から　色々な地球の話を聞きました
About the sea.
About the sky.
海の事
空の事
About the creatures
who live there.
そこに住む生き物の事
その話を聞く内に　地球に憧れを抱いて
As I heard these stories, I grew
more and more enamored of Earth.
As a result, I wanted more than
anything to come to Earth.
それでどうしても　地球に来てみたかったのです
And I wished to establish
peaceful relations with Earth.
そして　地球との和平を結びたかった
That creature,
could that be... a bird?
あれはもしかして　鳥
Yes, a black-tailed gull.
ええ　ウミネコです
An animal that flies through the sky!
They really do exist, don't they?
空を飛ぶ生き物　本当に居たのですね
It is just as you said, Slaine!
スレインの言った通り
My life was saved by Princess
Asseylum that day...
僕はあの時　アセイラム姫に　命を救われた
If it weren't for her,
I wouldn't be alive now...
姫が居なかったら　今僕は　生きていない
So this time, I will
protect you, Your Highness!
だから　今度は僕が　姫を守るんだ
I mustn't divulge that
she is alive...
姫の事　漏らしてはいけないんだ
I won't let those who hope to exploit
the princess have their way...
姫を利用しようとする奴らの　好きにさせてはいけない
Be they Martian...
それが火星人であっても　地球人であっても
...or Terran.
I...
僕は…
How regretful Princess
Asseylum must be...
アセイラム姫も　さぞや無念であろう
To put her faith in inferior scum like
him and lose her life as a result...
このような劣等民族を信用し　命を落とされるとは
Milord Cruhteo.
クルーテオ伯爵
What is it?
どうした
We've discovered something on
the island that we can't explain.
島で不可解な物を発見しました
The wreckage of another Kataphrakt, one not
belonging to Countess Femieanne.
フェミーアン伯爵とは別のカタフラクトの残骸です
This is the one that fell
to Earth 15 years ago...!
これは　15年前　地球に降下した
The Deucalion...!
It can't be!
デューカリオ
まさか…
The unit's Aldnoah drive
had been removed.
機体からは　アルドノアドライブが抜き取られています
What?! No, it is no
cause for concern.
何
いや　案ずる事はあるまい
They cannot activate
the Aldnoah.
奴らにアルドノアを起動する事は出来ぬ
What is so amusing?
貴様　何がおかしい
Nothing...
いえ　何も
もう良い　殺せ
Enough of this.
Kill him.
Not yet, Count Cruhteo.
待たれよ　クルーテオ卿
誇り高き　我ら軌道騎士を愚弄するなど
He makes a mockery of the
proud Orbital Knights.
I will spread your ashes
here on Earth.
この地球で灰にしてくれよ
Answer me, scum!
What made you laugh?!
答えろ　貴様何を笑った　何を笑った
Answer me. Without Aldnoah, the Terrans could
not have been the ones who slew Hellas.
答えよ　ヘラスを討ち取った者は
よもやアルドノアを持った者ではあるまいな
This is your punishment for what you've
done to Her Highness' beloved Earth...
姫様の愛した地球を　こんなにした報いです
Preposterous. They have no one
capable of activating it.
馬鹿な　起動できる者など
Only a handful of Versians
have come down to Earth,
地球に降りたヴァースの者は僅か　起動権を持つ者といえば
and the only ones possessing
the right of activation are...
It cannot be.
まさか…
Princess Asseylum?!
Is the princess still alive?!
アセイラム姫
姫は生きておられるのか
言え　姫はご無事なのか
Speak! Is she unharmed?!
答えぬか
Answer me, damn you!
If she were...
What would you do?
ご無事だと　どうされるのです
Assassinate her again?
また暗殺するのですか
What?
何
Was it not you who gave Sir Trillram
his orders? To kill the princess?
トリルラン卿に　命令したのでは　今度こそ殺せと
You dare suggest I-
貴様…
"If we let her live, my entire clan and its
followers will be branded as traitors."
生かしておけば　一族郎党逆賊だと
Why, you... You claimed to have
seen his death, as I recall.
貴様　トリルラン卿の最期を見たと申したな
Yes. I shot him.
ええ　僕が討ちました
では　隕石爆撃に巻き込まれたというのは
Then he did not get caught
in the meteor bombardment...
In the Nilokeras, with its
dimensional barrier?
次元バリアを装備した　ニロケラスがですか
I won't let you have your way...
あなたの　思い通りにはさせない
Her Highness... will
smash your plans.
姫様は　あなたの　野望を　砕く
Princess Asseylum... is alive?
That is impossible.
アセイラム姫が　生きておられる
そんなはずは…
It can't be!
まさか　貴様は真実を知り　一人で姫を探していたのか
You learned the truth and went out in
search of the princess on your own?
Telling no one, for fear
of alerting the traitors...
逆賊に悟られぬよう　誰にも明かさず　たった一人で…
Alone, without support...!
Willing to risk being captured
and killed by us...
我らに捕まり　殺される危険も顧みず
Forgive me, Slaine.
許せ　スレイン
You have proven your loyalty
a thousand times over!
よくぞここまで忠義を尽くした
See to this man's injuries!
この者を手厚く介抱せよ
Yes, Milord!
はっ
I, too, swore loyalty
to Her Highness...
私も姫に忠義を誓った者
Those traitors who dared to lay
a hand on her Highness will pay!
姫に手を掛けた反逆者　許しておかぬ
Put me through to
United Earth Headquarters!
地球連合本部に連絡を取れ
Offer a cease-fire and request their
assistance in locating the princess!
休戦を申し込むと同時に　アセイラム姫捜索の協力を願うと
We will identify those who made a mockery
of the Orbital Knights and punish them!
我ら軌道騎士を愚弄した者を必ずや突き止め　成敗してくれる
Milord Cruhteo! An object
is approaching from orbit!
クルーテオ伯爵　軌道上より接近する物体があります
何　また隕石爆撃か
What? Another meteor bombardment?
No, Milord!
いえ　減速率からみて　密度はずっと低いと思われます
Given its rate of deceleration,
it is far less dense!
It is adjusting its entry trajectory.
Estimated landing point is...
落下軌道を修正しています　落着予想地点は…
...this Landing Castle!
我が揚陸城
What happened?
何が起こった
あれは　ディオスクリア
That's... the Dioscuria!
Count Saazbaum?
ザーツバルム卿か
I see... It is all clear now!
そうか　そういう事か
The mastermind of
the assassination plot was...
姫の暗殺を企てたのは…
Ready my Tharsis!
私のタルシスを…
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:つっちー   翻译:mam&低音子   校对:小可&zwx   时间轴:框子   压制:河蟹
決めつけばかり　自惚れを着た
チープなhokoriで　音荒げても
棚に隠した　哀れな　恥に濡れた鏡の中
都合の傷だけひけらかして
手軽な強さで勝取るの術を
どれだけ磨いでも気はやつれる
ふらついた思想通りだ
愛-same-CRIER　愛撫-save-LIAR
Eid-聖-Rising HELL
愛してる　Game世界のDay
Don't-生-War　Lie-兵士-War-World
Eyes-Hate-War
A-Z Looser-Krankheit-Was IS das
Leben, was ist das?
Signal, Siehst du das?
Rede, die du nicht weisst
Aus eigenem Willen
Leben, was ist das?
Signal, Siehst du das?
Rede, die du nicht weisst
Sieh mit deinen Augen